Cursor is the most popular
AI-powered coding program.  The cursor
increases
programmers' efficiency, allows startups to
quickly develop projects from scratch,
and even enables
people with little experience in
development to create programs.  In this video, I'll explain how
to work with your cursor most
effectively, how to configure it for best
results, what problems you might encounter and how to
solve them, and how to avoid wasting a ton of
money.  Let's go.  Hi, my
name is Oleg.  By day I'm a programmer, and
in the evening I'm more of a vibe coder.  I write my
projects, test various
AI tools, check what works
and what doesn't.  For the past few months, I've
been using the cursor both when developing
my fives and when solving real-world
work problems.  It really changes the
approach, makes it more effective.
However, at the very beginning of working with the cursor,
I encountered many problems that
no one talked about on the Internet.  That's why in
this video I want to cover not only the
basic cursor issues, but also the more
subtle aspects that I
initially had difficulty with.  But let's start from the
beginning.  You've probably tried
writing programs using chpt.  This
works well overall, but
there are a few problems with this approach.  Each
time you need to copy the result of the task
, save the file on your computer,
run it, check it, and then
edit it again.  Then, to
continue developing the program, you need to
copy the contents of all files into one
promt and send it back to the GPT chat.
This works for small projects and
scripts, but is absolutely unbearable for
normal projects consisting of
dozens of files.  To solve this
problem, a cursor was invented.  The cursor is a
code editor with Ei functions.  It is
built on the basis of Visual Studio CD,
so it has a familiar interface for developers
: a file browser, tabs for
editing, and a terminal.  And the most
interesting thing is on the AI ​​panel.  Here
we can communicate with the neural network and give
it various tasks.  We can choose the
operating mode and the LMKA version.  The most
interesting mode in the cursor is
Agent Mode.  It can create,
edit, and run code itself, without
requiring any manual intervention.  Let's choose it
.  Let's take Clot 4et
with a thinking mode as a model.  If
this model is not available for you, you can
enable it in the Cursor section,
Preferences, Cursor Settings, Models.
Let's ask him to write a simple
snake in the browser.  I write: "Let's make an
unusual snake in the browser."  We see that
it has created the file, asks us to confirm
the changes, and is also waiting for confirmation
to run the command that opens the
HTML in the browser.  Click Run.  We see a ready-made
working game, the code of which we haven’t even
touched.  Amazing.  Now
let's make the work in the cursor even cooler.
Let's move on to the settings.  Basic
cursor settings.  While the agent is writing code, it sometimes
needs to run commands frequently.  And all
these commands require confirmation from the
user.  To avoid slowing down
development, we can disable the mandatory
requirement for app commands from the user.
Let him apply the changes and run
any necessary commands himself.  Open
the cursor, Preferences, cursor Settings,
chat, autor run mode.  Let's turn it on.
Now the cursor will not ask us for
permission.  It's much faster to
work with.  Let's open a new chat using the
plus button and delete the current code.  Let's write a
basic minesweeper for playing in a
browser and run it.  Now the agent
is developing without our approval.
After a couple of minutes, the browser opens, and
we can play the classic game of Minesweeper
.  Cool.  Everything works fine in this game
, but the images are
made using standard mods.  Let's
make this game have
original sprites.  We can
make them using the GPT4O
image generator, which is now available in the
GPT chat.  It handles
any kind of images very well.  To allow
the cursor to generate such images on
the fly, as needed, with the required
template and parameters, let's connect the
MCP, which will be responsible for
the generation.  What is MCP?  MCP is a
protocol for connecting any LLM and
external tools.  The MCP provides
commands that the neuron can call
when it needs them and with the parameters
it needs.  Let's connect the
image generator MCP server.  Let's go
to his GitHub repository.  This server
requires manual download of source code
.  Okay, let's clone it using Git
Clone.  Run yarn install and yarn
build as described in the
repository instructions.  Then we copy
the configuration, go to the
preferences cursor, the settings cursor mcp tools
or tools and integrations.  Click add
custom mcp.  We replace the contents of the file with the
server config and then change the path to the dox
in our downloaded repository.
Next we need an Open AI key to
generate images using the API.   Let
's go to platform.com, i.com.  Log in to the
settings app and create a new secret key.
We create an appic key and copy the value.
We insert open K as the value. We see
that the server appears in the MCP Tools list.
We restart and it turns green.  Now
it is ready for use.  Now we
can type in the chat withLm and the cursor
will generate and replace the emoji with our
unique images.  Let's do it.
We write: "Replace emoji and fills with
sprites."  Generate and save sprites with
our tool.  Use low
quality for images.  It starts
generating images, but they don't
appear.  There is no folder where
he wants to save them.  I'm stopping.
Please create a folder first.  OK.
Generating images again.  Now they
appear in the folder.  We wait for
all the images to be generated.  Then he replaces the emojis
with pictures.  Let's look at the result.  The cells
don't have a normal color because the sprites
for them were generated
invisible for some reason.  Let's return the fill to them, as
before.  Okay, everything works
fine now.  Instead of emojis, we see cool,
unique pictures.
Let's talk about Rules.  Rules in the cursor
allow you to reuse prompts
multiple times by specifying them in just
one place in the Rules section.  And as an
example, let's return to image generation.  In
my original prompt, I clearly wrote
the name of the MCP server, and also explicitly
specified the value of the quality low parameter,
since otherwise it will want to generate
high-quality images, and each
image will be very expensive.
To avoid writing this manually each time,
we can put this instruction in the rules.
Go to the preferences cursor, then the settings cursor, then the
rules cursor.  We click add rule and write
our service prompt there, so that
if it wants to generate
an image, it would use
this particular MCP with these parameters.   We'll
also add an instruction so that it
checks for the existence of the folder for
images, since they are not saved
if the folder does not exist.  Now we can test
this rule by asking it
to generate a picture of a mushroom in the
Mushrooms folder.  Let's launch.  We see that
Anironka checked the existence of the folder,
created the necessary directory, and then
started generating the image with the
low quality parameter.  Great, the rule
works.  Similarly, we can
write other basic instructions
or restrictions that apply to all
our projects.  But what if we want to
use certain rules not
always, but only for some of our
projects?  Is it then necessary to
constantly create and delete rules manually?
No.  Project Ruls can be used for this
.  They work only at the
project folder level, in addition to the
global rules we specified
earlier.  To register Project Rules,
you need to create a tocursor folder and a
Rules folder, and then register
text files with the tom mdc extension inside.
As an example, we can write the rule
images.mc.  We write: "All images
associated with this project should be
stored in the Sprites folder."  And an important
point: all Project Rules have a Rules
Type.  In it we can configure when
this rule will be triggered.  Manual,
if we attach it to the dialogue manually.  Agent
requested.  If the agent read the description of
the rule, he decided that it was needed right
now.  Autoch, when rules are triggered
when working with certain types of
files, certain folders, and so
on.  We can configure any
file path pattern.  Useful if a project,
for example, has many modules with different
libraries, languages, and frameworks.
It is easy to separate the rules for them.  And
always.  The rule will always apply to
this project.  Let's select it and
save the file.  Let's write to the agent: "Create
an image of a mushroom."  We see that Nero
herself understood that the image needs to
be saved in the sprites folder.  Ready.
Let's dig a little deeper into the details.  Let's talk
about context.  Context is everything that
our neuron sees and knows at the moment
.  The agent in the cursor
is currently just a chat with a lmka plus
tools that allow him
to edit files and call commands in the
terminal.  Therefore, the context of the agents
cursor is just the contents of the
current chat plus rules.  This is important
to remember, because sometimes it seems like the
cursor is some kind of magical thing
that knows and can do everything.  This is wrong.   The
model context may be cluttered with
various garbage or, conversely, may not
contain the information we need.  To
work with it as effectively as possible, I
have developed the following rules.  The first is
to break big tasks into small
steps.  Large tasks may require
serious work and the creation of a large
number of files.  This greatly obscures the
context of the model.  She can get confused,
get stuck in one place, forget about the
existence of files that she
wrote herself.  The best LMKs at the current stage of
development cope well with simple
tasks of the type.  Write one
function, correct one nuance in the
program, add one button that
performs one specific action, and so
on.  It is also desirable that the result of
one such small task be easy
to check in order to immediately detect and
fix bugs, if any.  As
an example, let's consider the following problem.
We'll create a program that will
scan news in the AI ​​section of the
Techcrunch website, select the five most
interesting ones, and publish them as a
digest to a Telegram channel.  And then
we can use this program to
run it once a day.  I can break
it down into steps that gradually add new
features.  And after implementing all the
subtasks, the program will work as
we need.  And what's important is that the program will
work at each stage and can
be tested.  That is, there will be no
moment where the program does not start at all
.  These are the steps I have highlighted.   The
first function, which gets links
to HTML pages, is the base
we'll start with.  Next we will add
link filtering.  Then we will receive the
news text via the link, and then
process only those news items that are
not yet in our database.  Then we'll add
posting to the Telegram channel and then select the
five most interesting ones.  Now let's get
to the implementation.  Let's create a new project.   Let
's write a problem: write a simple function
that extracts links from an HTML page.
Let's launch the crunch section with a link to the AI.
Great, it works.  Plus the code doesn't look
overcomplicated.
It will do.  Now let's implement the second step.  And
we will need the second rule for working with
context.  Create a new chat for
each new subtask.  This is necessary so that the
chat context is not overloaded with unnecessary
information, thoughts, and attempts
to implement previous tasks.  Let's
create a new chat by clicking on the plus.
Let's write the following problem there.  Write
a function that filters links.  by
substring.  Put this function in a
separate file.  I am writing this exact
query because the links found in the
previous step show that all target
links to articles have this format.
They contain the date in their address, which
means we can easily filter out
links leading to news if we
only look for those that contain /2025/
in their address.  I also ask that the function
be created in a separate file so as not to
overload the original function with a large
amount of code.  Okay, I got the code, but it
looks like the model created three
filter functions for us instead of one.  Well,
let's remove the unnecessary functions that
filter by extension and substitution, and
also fix the example code.  By the way,
you can use smart
code editing with Tab here.  I just
put a pointer where something is
wrong.  And the cursor itself offers us to delete
and rename variables.  This
works great in simple cases like this.  I press
Tab and it is applied.  Let's launch it and
check.  Yeah, the filtering works.
Cool.  Let's move on to the third step.  We will
receive news texts via the link.
Let's open a new chat.  We write a
function that retrieves the text of an
HTML page at the specified address.
Write it in a separate file.  We see that
our request uses the context of the
currently open file.  Now in
the context of the linkfilter, since we have it
open.  If I switch to the link
extractor file, it will appear in the context.
What does such a context influence in general?  It
influences what the neural network sees at
the start of the chat.  For all attached
files, she sees the path to them plus their
contents.  If you don't attach any
files, the neural network will search for them
automatically, either by browsing the
project's folders and files or by running a
content search.  This may not work well on
large projects with a huge number of
files.  The model may not see all the
places that affect the current task.   The
third rule follows from this:
attach to the current chat via
adcntek those and only those files that
affect the implementation of the current task.
Since we are now creating a separate function
that downloads the text of an HTML page
via a link, we don’t need existing files
, so we can remove them from the
context.  Let's delete them.  Let's launch.
We get a function that can be
tested on a single link.  As an example,
I will write a link to an article from those crunch.
I see truncated content in the console.
I'm editing it so it doesn't get cut off by tabs.
Now the console has the full contents, but I
can't find the actual fragments from the
article there.  Yeah, that's what happens when the
console cuts off text from a very
long length.  Let's
save to a file using magic tap.
Yeah.  Let's launch.  Open the saved
file in the browser.  Great, we have the article.
I'll double-check the file text to
make sure the news text is in
our file.  They are loaded by the browser
on the go.  Great.  It is there, but the
file size is too large.  Almost 180,000
characters, although the article itself is
small.  The problem is that the file
contains a lot of useless HTML, JS,
CSS code that we don’t need to
extract information.  Let's delete
it.  Let's ask to get rid of it inside
our HTMLCH so that the function returns
only the text of the article without the technical
code.  Let's write a function from the right so that it
returns only the text content of
the page, excluding HTML tags, CSS and
JavaScript code.  Let's specify the HTML file Fcher in the context
.  Let's remove the unnecessary FCH
Content with encoding function.  I don't really understand what the
difference is.  Plus it's not
used anywhere.  Let's launch.  Yeah, we're
being asked to use the Beautiful
sublibrary.  To do this, I will create a
virtual environment for Python so that I can
install libraries only within it.
I see that the Request library is still missing
.  I install them and launch them.  Great.
I see a file with text without unnecessary junk.
And this file contains all the necessary text.
Plus its length is now less than 4,000
characters.  Cool.  We can move on to the
next step.  Now let's try to
implement interaction with the database
to download only those news items
that we don't have yet.  We will need a
database plus a function that
works with it, a collector and a
link parser.  I suggest
using SQL Lite as a database so you don't have to worry about
launching and connecting.  SQL Lite is a
single-file database.  It is
much lighter than any of its other
alternatives, but still works with
the same SQL queries as Postgress and
MySQL.  It can easily be replaced with another
normal database in the future if
we need it.  Let's write a
proposal.  Write a function that will
call extract links from url with
our link parameter.  Filter
links using filter links by
substring with the substring 2025. Then
check whether each
link exists in the SQL Lite database.
The connection also needs to be implemented.  If
the link is not in the database, retrieve its text
using fetchtek content and save it to
our database.  The database must contain the columns
ID, URL, content and fetched.
We select all our Python files, as
they are needed to implement this task.
Let's launch.  We receive the news processor file.
Let's launch it.  We see that he is pumping out
news.  A news database file was also created
, which stores our
database.  Let's see what's in it via
Debiver.  Debiver is a universal
control panel for any database.
I create a new connection, select SQL
Lite, and open our file.  I see that
there is an articles table in the database.  It is not clear
that 38 records have been preserved.  Let's
check that
no duplicates are saved when we restart it.  Yeah,
four more added.  Let's restart again
.  I see that zero new ones have been added
.  I'll check it using an SQL query.
The number of unique URLs is 42.
Excellent, all articles are unique, everything
works as it should.  Now we'll implement
sending to the Telegram public.  I created a
news channel.  Now I will create a bot
using botfr.  I need his token.  And
I will add this bot to my channel as an admin
so that it can post messages.  I'll write a
test message in the channel and forward
it to botuser Info.  It gives the
sender's ID.  This way you can find out the ID of
our channel, so that you can then use it
to send messages to it.  Let's add
our Telegram Bot token and channel ID to
Nfile.
In development, it is common practice to store all our
settings and secrets in such files.  And by
default the cursor cannot see point N
files in the project.  Therefore, to
some extent, our secrets will be
safe, since we do not leak them
to the LLM provider’s server.  And a couple more
important points.  First, since we're
going to be working with Telegram, it's best to
let the neural network know the documentation for
libraries that work with Telegram.  For
this, I'll add the super-useful MCP Contaxt
7. I'll grab its Config from GitHub.  I'll add it to
our MCP JON.  Great.
[music]
The link to the config for this tool
is in the video description.  And secondly,
since we are going to change the
news processing process already implemented in the
new processing file, we may
accidentally break something that was working before.
Therefore, for safety, I will commit the
current state of the project to Git.  Git
is a version control system.  It
allows you to save chains of changes to
text files, fork different versions,
and revert to previous
code states.  I'll ask the cursor to create a
gitgnor file to ignore files
that are not related to our code.
Great, the file is ready.  Now we write
git git in the terminal and then
we can commit the files in the
git tab and save them with the init message.
[music]
Now our files are safely stored in
giIT.  And even if the cursor accidentally deletes
one of them, we can easily return
to the previous state by executing one
command.  Working with IT is critical when
developing in cursor to avoid
fatal changes from neurons.  Now let
's write the promt.  After extracting the
news text, add functionality
that will send a message to
Telegram using our bot.  Telegram
bot token and channel ID are located at point
Nfile.  Use contact 7 and don't look into
our secrets.  I ask you not to look at
the tochfile, since the cursor does not have
access to it anyway.  Please use
Contax 7 to correctly use
Telegram integration, referring to
the documentation.  Let's launch.  We see that he is
searching for libraries and looking at their
documentation.  Ready.  He added
requirements txt to make it easier to work with
dependencies.  Let's install them using the UVP
Install Air requirements command.  Let's launch.  Yeah,
nothing was sent because there is
no new news.  Let's delete one news item from the
database and restart.
Great.  We see the news in our Telegram
public group.
Sending to channel works.
[music] We will use a
similar approach to select the
top five news items using integration with
Open Router via Client Open AI.
We will pass there the base path to the Open
Router, the model name and AP.  Let's add them to
the file.  We'll be uploading
all our news to Promtechnironki and expecting a full digest from her
.
We will use the
Gemini 2 c5 Flash as a model, since it is very
cheap and at the same time has more or less
normal intelligence.   Let's
fill in ENF and write down the promt.  I'll make the
model select the five best articles
and return them as a ready-made digest for
sending to Telegram.  Use the Open AI
library to which the
model, base, and IPEN must be passed.
Use contex 7 and don't look at the dot
nfile.  We receive the code, launch it,
see the error, and send it to the chat.
Let's start it again.  We see that the digest has
been successfully sent.  There are five news items in it.
Great.  The program is ready.  Let's finish
this project.  I'll tell you what else I
use in the cursor.  Project Rules and
context files.  In large projects,
Project Rules are critical.  Without them, you'll
either have to attach half the project to the chat
or pray that
the model will figure out how and what works in it
.  You can
reference specific files in your project rules, indicating
them as examples or as places where
new code needs to be added.  It is possible to prescribe
code style recommendations and approaches.
Alternatively, you can generate rules
based on your project using a cursor.
You can also
specify
project-specific MCP servers in the dotpcoorp folder.  They will
only run with this project.  They
can be specified in the mcp.jonjson file.
You can also commit the tocursor folder to Git
and push your repository so that
all team members have the same MCP rules
.  Which model is better
to use?  There are many models available in the cursor
.  You can even add
custom ones via API integration.  In this
video I compared all the best models
available at the moment.  The most
optimal for development is Clot
4 SNET, included in Thinking Mode.
Queries using it are included in the
cursor plan.  Now you can make an unlimited
number of such requests without
paying anything extra.  What is Max Mode?  Max Mode
is a mode in which we pay not for
a subscription, but for the number of
tokens used by the model.  It allows us
to use more advanced models
such as Clot 4 OPUS and O3 Pro.  Since
their AI is so expensive, I wouldn't
recommend using these models in a
cursor unless you have an unlimited budget
for wipe coding.  Is it worth buying a
subscription?  Without a subscription, Cursor
offers a two-week trial with a
limited number of requests.  For
$20 per month, we get unlimited
queries, plus several features
and increased model context.  If
you use Macmod, you will have to
pay on top of this amount.  If you're
actively working with code, then such a
subscription is really cheap, since
calls to, for example, a standard CLD 4
Sonet over IP would be very expensive,
especially if the conversation grows.  Here
I did a Redmi generation and
spent 13 cents.  That is only
150 such requests per month for
$20.  Quite a few.  That's why I
always advocate for subscriptions.  They are more profitable
than tools using apitokens.
If you're wondering why working with code and
tools is so expensive,
check out this video.  There I
explain the complete algorithm for working with the
tools.  Now let's talk about the
cursor alternative.  WНСserve is the
most cursor-like
development environment, equipped with Agentum.
The interface is exactly the same as in Cursor.
We can give tasks to the agent, it can
change files and call commands.  However,
Clot models are not currently available in Winserf, but there is a big discount on
GPT 4.1.  Plus, the subscription costs less than the
cursor - $15, but is limited to
five hundred credits.  It makes sense to take it
if you don't like models and don't
write code super-intensively, since there are
no unlimited requests.  The second
competitor-cursor is Cloudcode.  Recently, it
became available on reasonable terms for
users who purchased a
minimum subscription for $20.
It's not really a development environment, but rather a
console utility like CINE.  But with
the help of extensions, she can easily
see the file opened by the user, the
line selected by the user, and so
on.  The only model that can be
used here is the Claude from Antropic.
Minimum subscription is 20 bucks.  The limits
allow you to work normally with Sonet and a little
bit.  If you want to hard
-code with Opus, there are more
expensive subscriptions with higher limits.
It makes sense to use if you are a big
fan of Anthropopic or want to work with
CLD 4 OPUS without overpaying millions.  And
all these development environments support
MCP.  Here is a short list of my favorites.
Contek 7 searches for libraries by
keywords and looks at their documentation.  Playri
can open a browser, watch
your frontend work, or retrieve
information from the internet.  To see how it
works, watch my video about MCP.
GitHub and Gitlab allow you to manage
your repositories, create Mershik
quests, and start and stop
pipelines.  Superbase allows you to quickly
create projects from scratch using the
Superbase database and the NextJz application.
Superbase is a very friendly
database that can act as a
backend.  It is very easy to operate.   A
must if you want to start a project
from scratch as quickly as possible.  And GETSG is
my MCP that allows you
to reuse project template code.
Link in the description.  For example, I can
very quickly make a project that works
in 3D in the browser using a template from
Getк.  See the description for configs of all MCP servers
.  What
programming languages ​​does the cursor work with?  The cursor
can work with any
programming language, just like it
does in Visual Studio Code.  All you need to do is
connect the extension with your
programming language.  By default,
the cursor only works with JavaScript.
How to use a cursor safely and not
leak all your secret information?
The cursor won't save any data
if you enable privacy mode, but it's best
to make sure it doesn't even see it.
Therefore, I suggest disallowing him from
using the Cut command.  F and in the rules,
write down that it doesn’t try to look at
our secrets, otherwise it will furiously
try to look at the contents of our
file.  Let's quickly run through some
common mistakes.  First.
You click on the retrain endlessly, the dialogue does not
continue.  Create a new one.  So,
the context of the previous one has ended.  Second.
The model has forgotten about its changes or
task and is walking in circles.  Create a dialogue
again.  Most likely, the task was either
too difficult or the dialogue was too
long.  Third.  The model has deleted the files you
need.  Always commit only
working changes and revert to the
previous state via rollback if
necessary.  Results.  The cursor is a
truly powerful tool that allows you
to accelerate your coding to incredible
speeds, but you need to be extremely careful with it
.  Cing Ei requires more
attention to detail than regular
programming.  You need to remember the
basic rules and check all the code
written by the neural network, and then
development with LM will really
pay for itself and won't drown you in endless
bugs.  I think cursors and similar
tools
will really change the way we write
programs in the coming months or years.  Things will probably change
even faster.  So subscribe to the
channel.  Here I will review everything I
have tried, show my experiments
with neural networks, as well as small successes in
my personal projects.  And also visit
my Telegram channel.  There I get in
touch much more often, writing down thoughts,
jokes, and nuances in development with Ii.
Link in the description.  See you.  U